The greatest battle lies within.
Spider-Man 3 is a action, adventure, science fiction film directed by Sam Raimi.
The seemingly invincible Spider-Man goes up against an all-new crop
of villains—including the shape-shifting Sandman.
While Spider-Man’s superpowers are altered by an alien organism, his alter ego, Peter Parker,
deals with nemesis Eddie Brock and also gets caught up in a love triangle.
Spider-Man / Peter Parker, played by Tobey Maguire.
Mary Jane Watson, played by Kirsten Dunst.
New Goblin / Harry Osborn, played by James Franco.
Sandman / Flint Marko, played by Thomas Haden Church.
Venom / Eddie Brock, played by Topher Grace.
Gwen Stacy, played by Bryce Dallas Howard.
Spider-Man 3 is a 2007 American superhero film based on
the Marvel Comics character Spider-Man.
Produced by Columbia Pictures, Marvel Entertainment, and Laura Ziskin Productions, and distributed by Sony Pictures
Releasing, it was directed by Sam Raimi from a screenplay he co-wrote with his brother Ivan and Alvin Sargent.
It is the third  installment in Raimi's Spider-Man trilogy (2002–2007), and
the sequel to Spider-Man (2002) and Spider-Man 2 (2004).
The film stars Tobey Maguire as Peter Parker / Spider-Man, alongside Kirsten Dunst, James Franco, Thomas
Haden Church, Topher Grace, Bryce Dallas Howard, James Cromwell, Rosemary Harris, and J.
It also marks the final acting appearance of Cliff Robertson before his
retirement from acting in the same year and his subsequent death in 2011.
Set a year after the events of Spider-Man 2, the film follows Peter Parker (Maguire) as he prepares for his future with Mary Jane Watson (Dunst), while facing multiple threats: Flint Marko (Church), Uncle Ben's true killer who becomes the Sandman after a freak accident; Harry Osborn (Franco), his
former best friend who is now aware of Peter's identity and seeks to avenge his father; an extraterrestrial symbiote that increases his abilities but amplifies his anger and other negative traits; and Eddie Brock (Grace), a rival photographer who becomes the symbiote's second host Venom.
Development of Spider-Man 3 began immediately after the
successful release of Spider-Man 2 for a 2007 release.
During preproduction, Raimi wanted two villains, Harry Osborn and Sandman.
At the request of producer Avi Arad, he added Venom to the list, and
the producers also requested the addition of Gwen Stacy.
Principal photography for the film began in January 2006 and took place in Los Angeles
and Cleveland before moving to New York City from May until July 2006.
Additional pick-up shots were made after August and
the film wrapped in October 2006.
During post-production, Sony Pictures Imageworks
created over 900 visual effects shots.
Composer Danny Elfman, who had scored the previous installments, decided not to return due to creative differences and conflicts
with Raimi during production of the previous film, so Christopher Young composed the score in Elfman's absence.
With an estimated production budget of $258–350 million, the film was the
most expensive film ever made at the time of its release.
Spider-Man 3 premiered on April 16, 2007, in Tokyo, and was released in the
United States in both conventional and IMAX theaters on May 4.
The film grossed $895.9 million worldwide, making it the highest-grossing film of the trilogy, the
third-highest-grossing film of 2007 and the tenth-highest-grossing film of all time at the time of its release.
It was also the highest-grossing Spider-Man film until it was surpassed by Spider-Man: Far From Home in 2019,
and Raimi's highest-grossing film until Doctor Strange in the Multiverse of Madness (2022).
Unlike the previous installments, Spider-Man 3
received mixed reviews from critics.
A sequel, Spider-Man 4, was set to be released in 2011, followed by a Venom spin-off
film along with a fifth and sixth installment, but all were canceled.
The film explores themes of amnesia, dual identity, love of
one's life, loss of loved one, forgiveness.
The tone is thought_provoking.